Here, are two histograms comparing the number of dogs that I
لدينا هنا مدرجان تكراريان للمقارنة بين عدد الكلاب التي
saw on weekdays to the number of dogs I saw on weekends from last year.
رأيتها في أيام الأسبوع وعدد الكلاب التي رأيتها في عطلات نهاية الأسبوع من العام الماضي.
You will notice that the tallest bins for
ستلاحظون أن النطاقات الأطول لكل من
both weekdays and weekends are associated with 13 dogs.
أيام الأسبوع وعطلات نهاية الأسبوع مرتبطة بعدد 13 كلبًا.
So the number of dogs I expect to see are
لذا فإن عدد الكلاب التي أتوقع رؤيتها هي
essentially the same for weekdays as on weekends.
نفسها في كلٍ من أيام الأسبوع وعطلات نهاية الأسبوع.
And the measures of center would basically be the same here.
وستكون مقاييس المركز في الأساس نفس الشيء هنا.
Both have a mean, median,
كلاهما له وسط ومتوسط
and mode that are about 13 dogs.
ومنوال وهو 13 كلبًا تقريبًا.
But something is different about these two distributions.
ولكن هناك شيء مختلف بشأن هذين التوزيعين.
So what's the difference?
إذًا ما الفرق؟
Well, the difference is how spread out the data are for each group.
حسنًا، الاختلاف هنا هو في مدى انتشار البيانات لكل مجموعة.
You can see that the number of dogs I see on weekdays, ranges from 10-16.
يمكنكم ملاحظة أن عدد الكلاب التي أراها خلال أيام الأسبوع يتراوح بين 10 إلى 16 كلبًا.
While on weekends, it ranges from 6-18.
بينما يتراوح بين 6 إلى 18 خلال عطلات نهاية الأسبوع.
In the upcoming sections,
في الأقسام القادمة،
we will look at the most common ways to measure the spread of our data.
سنلقي نظرة على الطرق الأكثر شيوعًا لقياس انتشار بياناتنا.